Austin Schaffer

(703) 258 9423 | schaffer.austin.t@gmail.com github.com/AustinTSchaffer | linkedin.com/in/AustinTSchaffer | linktr.ee/AustinTSchaffer Last Updated - March 19, 2024

Statement of Purpose

I am a software engineer with 8 years of professional experience. I am most proficient with cloud software, but I also have experience in many other domains including DevOps, edge computing, desktop applications, system administration, and application support. I love working with large volumes of data. I love designing the architecture for new applications. I love investigating issues with systems, proposing solutions, and implementing those solutions. My aim is to increase reliability. lower cost, build cool things, and learn everything that I can.

Work Experience

Staff Software Engineer

Everactive - Cloud Team

September 2021 - Current

TimescaleDB, PostgreSQL, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Kotlin, Go, Typescript, Python, GitLab, Terraform, Docker, MQTT

Multi-faceted cross-team software engineering role, from edge to cloud computing

Design, architect, and develop real-time data streaming infrastructure for batteryless IoT devices

Develop cloud-native distributed applications comprising REST APIs, microservices, message gueues, and DBs

Routinely investigate the health and cost of data ingest and storage, and implement improvements

Routinely investigate performance issues with production TimescaleDB SQL queries for time-series data

Routinely investigate issues with LTE Ubuntu Core gateways deployed at customer sites, using Tailscale

Designed and built a battery-powered air-gapped field tool for flashing sensor firmware using a Raspberry Pi

Designed and implemented a real-time data egress service, supporting both HTTP and MQTT

Designed and built an airgapped version of our cloud software

Infrastructure Engineer (DevOps)

Merkle Inc. - Datascience (DSCI)

April 2020 - September 2021 1 year, 6 months

AWS (EC2, AMIs, Lambda, EMR, S3, IAM), Python/Anaconda, Linux, Bitbucket, Docker, Terraform, Packer

AWS admin and DevOps resource for Merkle's data science team

Managed infrastructure in AWS using Terraform and Bitbucket Pipelines

Deployed Python data science workloads to EC2 instances and EMR clusters

Developed Python packages for interfacing with vendor systems including AWS and Snowflake

Improved the team's dependency management systems using Poetry, simplifying conda environments

Maintained an EC2 AMI build and release process, keeping dev and prod environments secure and up to date

Worked across teams to ensure secure IAM users, roles, and policies are in place for cross-account access

Software Developer

January 2017 - April 2020

Atlas Systems, Inc. - Devgineers

3 years, 4 months

Python, Git, Docker, Debian Linux, C# (.NET Framework and .NET Core), Linode, Azure, Azure DevOps

Developed ETL pipelines for archival metadata using Python

Provisioned and managed Linux VMs for docker-compose environment deployments

Configured automated build pipelines in Azure Devops

Set up private package registries for Python and C# projects

Trained development and data migration teams on Git, Python, Docker, SQL, and Azure DevOps Build Pipelines Lead developer for Atlas's C# .NET Framework applications

Provided technical support for Atlas's core products, plugins, and hosted services

Researched and developed automated workflows for Development and IT processes

Software Developer I - Quick Response Team (QRT)

Ferguson Enterprises, Inc. - Ferguson IT

Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

5 months

Provided tier-3 technical support to IT staff and warehouse employees Researched problems with in-house WMS, developed in uniBasic Resolved issues with production data, through direct database queries

Austin Schaffer

(703) 258 9423 | schaffer.austin.t@gmail.com <u>github.com/AustinTSchaffer</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/AustinTSchaffer</u> | <u>linktr.ee/AustinTSchaffer</u> Last Updated - March 19, 2024

Education

Georgia Tech (Georgia Institute of Technology) - College of Computing

August 2022 - Currently Enrolled

M.S. Computer Science (OMSCS)

Currently pursuing an M.S in Computer Science through Georgia Tech's online masters program (OMSCS)

Christopher Newport University

August 2011 - May 2016 cum laude, 3.57 GPA

B.S. Computer Science, Computer Engineering

CNU Honors Program

Vice President, Upsilon Pi Epsilon, CS Honor Society

PCSE Lab Assistant and CS Tutor

Certifications

Microsoft - Programming in C# (Exam 70-483)

(ISC)² - Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP)

April 2017

Volunteer Experience

Software Development and DevOps Volunteer

March 2021 - November 2023

Code4Cville

Web scraping, data engineering, NLP+ML, DevOps, consulting

Participated in a sentiment analysis project over a collection of public comments, all pertaining to a new guidance put forth by Virginia's executive branch

Participated in community projects for Code4Cville's pro-bono consulting division

Served as an Oracle Cloud administrator for various teams and projects

Mitigated cloud security concerns for Code4Cville's Oracle VPC and Linux instances

Managed a Jupyterhub instance for ongoing data science projects

Internship Experience

Intern - Preserving and Analyzing Airborne Science Observational Data Project

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016

6 months

4 months

NASA Langley Research Center

Worked with NASA data scientists to improve ICARTT data merge process

Developed an XML schema to configure data merge process

Incident Response Intern - Swisslog STAR Team

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Swisslog Logistics - Swisslog Warehouse and Distribution Services

Provided technical support to Swisslog clients

Project Manager - CNU Mobile Applications Development Team

May 2013 - Aug 2014

Information Technology Services - Christopher Newport University

1 year, 4 months

Developed CNU's first official mobile application using Telerik AppBuilder (HTML, JS, CSS)

Skills

Programming - Python, Kotlin, Golang, Typescript/Javascript, C# (.NET Core), SQL, HTML/CSS, Lua, F#, Java **Tools** - Git, Terraform, Docker/Containers, Linux, Markdown, Bash/Zsh, Packer, VSCode, PyCharm, IntelliJ **Infrastructure** - PostgreSQL, TimescaleDB, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Kafka Connect, RabbitMQ, Prometheus, Docker **Service Providers** - AWS, Aiven, Auth0, GitLab, GitHub, Azure, Linode, Digital Ocean, Oracle Cloud **Duties Performed** - Architecture Design, Code Reviews, Semantic Versioning, Dependency Management, Production Support, Application Forensics, Database Administration, System Administration, CI/CD